Michael Iodice

Littleton, CO 80127 | 617-835-0158 | miodice3@gmail.com

GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Blog

Full Stack Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React with a background in Real Estate Portfolio Management and Development. Strong skills in project management, communication and working in chaotic environments. Skilled in identifying the unspoken needs within individuals, projects and processes. Enjoys self taught learning and difficult projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with JavaScript and Ruby languages, React / Redux, Rails frameworks
Some experience with C++ / IOT devices, Docker, Postgres, SQL, ActiveRecord, GitHub collaborative workflow

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Automobile Emissions Analyzer github | UsefulTool.com | demo

React / Redux and Rails application comparing emissions data for any vehicle in the US federal database

- Aggregated data from 3 disjoint datasets by combining REST and graph based APIs. This enabled users to interact
 with the joined data sets via a web-based graph in React
- Computed electric vehicle emissions with Britain's Electric Utility API in order to provide real-time emissions data
- Managed state in React using Redux. State leveraged a flexible and dynamic model that enabled the application to grow in complexity over time

Sol-Search github | sol-search.com | demo

A Ruby on Rails full stack MVC application serving as a marketplace for renewable energy which significantly decreases the friction involved with pairing consumers and producers for renewable energy projects

- Incorporated Google OAuth to verify user accounts and 'confirm email' feature for non-Gmail signups to reduce spam
- Deployed production code to Heroku in order to achieve a public facing endpoint with a low operational overhead
- Configured user contracts in Postgres using a self-referential join with ActiveRecord. This enabled application users to participate as either party in an energy contract
- Implemented real time email updates when energy contracts are modified, driving user interaction by maintaining deal momentum

Motivational Box github | demo

A scratch made web connected lockbox complete with task list application. Box unlocks itself upon task list completion from a smartphone, optimized for minimum power consumption

- Developed web server using C++ to handle HTTP based interactions with mobile application. Service consisted of a single API with multiple endpoints and was deployed to a low cost microcontroller
- Integrated OLED display to enable simple application configuration and fun messaging to users
- Designed mobile application with embedded TinyDB database to enable persistence across application restarts

EXPERIENCE

Chatham Development Co.

Newton, MA

Project Management, Portfolio Management

09/2013 - 03/2020

- Managed sales of 7 large properties totaling \$85mm over 3 years. Coordinated between legal teams, property owners, brokerage firms and purchasers to ensure alignment across all parties involved
- Retained legal team and lead defense efforts to protect company from \$65MM of frivolous lawsuits
- Advised client on expense recovery strategies, ultimately yielding full recovery of \$250k in wages and legal fees,
 \$750k in unpaid trustee fees, and the withdrawal of initial frivolous lawsuit years ahead of schedule
- Transitioned company from paper systems to fully electronic systems with cloud backups for resilience

Brown Brothers Harriman

Boston, MA

Senior Client Account Manager, ETF Service Group

07/2010 - 08/2013

Automated an error prone 32 hour manual process to 30 minutes with Excel macros, FTP and a pivot table

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Time Online, Castle Rock, CO

Full Stack Software Engineering Program

09/2020 - 04/2021

Boston University

Boston, MA 05/2009

Bachelor of Arts in Economics